# Shiyi "Ashley" Yue

♦ (315) 746-9070 ♦ ashley.yue117@gmail.com ♦ San Francisco, CA ♦ LinkedIn ♦ Portfolio

## **PROFILE**

MS in Business Analytics candidate at UC Davis. A data-driven, passionate, and goal-oriented fast learner with strong competency in Python and SQL. Value positions that I can contribute to, learn from, and grow with.

**Specialties:** Data Manipulation, Data Visualization, Machine Learning, Hypothesis Testing, Experimental Design, Causal Inference Analysis, EDA, A/B Test, Time Series, Image Classification, Big Data, Business Intelligence

**Technologies:** MySQL, MS SQL Server, MongoDB, R, SPSS, Tableau, PowerBI, Python (Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Sk-Learn, SciPy, TensorFlow, PySpark), Advanced Excel, Advanced PowerPoint, AWS, GCP, HTML

Certifications: AWS Cloud Practitioner: GC2BYJN1QM4QQ93M, Tableau Desktop Specialist

## **EDUCATION**

# University of California, Davis

San Francisco, CA

Master of Science, Business Analytics (currently 3.75/4.0)

Expected Jun. 2023

Highlighted Coursework: Machine Learning, Advanced Statistics, Big Data, Data Management, Data Visualization Award: Beta Gamma Sigma Membership (Top 20%)

# **Southwest University of Political Science and Law**

Chongqing, CHN

Bachelor of Economics, Economic Statistics (3.77/4.0)

Sept. 2018 - Jun. 2022

Highlighted Coursework: Statistics, Data Mining, Time Series Analysis, Econometrics, Finance, Accounting

# State University of New York, Oswego

Oswego, NY

A one-year exchange program (3.83/4.0)

Aug. 2021 – May. 2022

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Fashom
Data Scientist (Practicum Project)

Miami, FL

Sept. 2022 – Current

A fast-paced e-commerce startup planning to offer B2B API solutions regarding personalized recommendations.

- Enhanced clothing attribute **image classification** algorithm accuracy from 30% to 80% by revamping the model architecture using transfer learning (ResNet) within **TensorFlow** and utilizing Data Augmentation.
- Reduced the cost and improved the training times significantly for the clothing attribute classification model by streamlining model training through effective utilization of **Google Cloud** Vertex Al
- Showcased exceptional **communication** skills by effectively communicating work progress on a weekly basis to both technical and non-technical stakeholders.
- Improved team productivity by creating reusable Python functions and fostering knowledge sharing, resulting in streamlined workflows and increased efficiency.

## PricewaterhouseCoopers (PwC)

Shenzhen, CHN

**Business Analyst Intern** 

Sept. 2021 – Dec. 2021

- Revealed valuable patterns and insights by leveraging MySQL, Python, and Tableau to extract, process, and visualize 27K + daily user engagement data from the client's website.
- Increased conversion prediction accuracy to 76% by applying **Logistic Regression** in Python to user engagement data, using significant features identified by Lasso Regression and business acumen.
- Achieved an 84% accuracy rate in forecasting weekly conversions by developing an ARIMA model in R
  that utilized user engagement metrics, enabling proactive business planning.

Founder Securities Shenzhen, CHN

**Industry Analyst Assistant** 

Apr. 2021 - Jul. 2021

A well-known industry consulting company in China.

- Revealed trends and seasonal patterns by performing EDA on 327K+ monthly sales records in the FMCG industry using Python and MySQL.
- Identified opportunities and threats for the FMCG industry by conducting a **SWOT** analysis.
- Contributed to 30-page industry reports with data visualization via Tableau, summarizing key patterns.